nationalcrm.com 2016-06-05

# Privacy Policy | Vtiger CRM

Vtiger is committed to respecting your privacy. After all, we exist thanks to our customers.

The following Privacy Policy statement outlines how we use your data. This statement applies to the services that we provide through our web properties. You will be notified of any changes to the Privacy Policy Statement via email or through a prominent notice on our website. In order to use Vtiger CRM On Demand you must consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy statement.

### Collection and Use of your Personal Information

While accessing Vtiger products and services, we may collect personal information from you such as your name, email address, language, and more. We use this personal information to:

  * Ensure that our site, products, and services are relevant to you
  * Notify you of billing or changes related to products or services that you receive from us
  * Send you newsletters, special offers, and information about new services, if you so request.

### Collection and Use of Non Personal Information

When you register for Vtiger CRM On Demand, or download and install our open source software,  we may collect non-personal information − data that does not permit direct association with any specific individual, such as your country and operating system. This information is used to help us improve our products and services.

### Stored Information

  * Personal Information: Your personal Information such as user name, password, email address will be used primarily for providing you access to the Vtiger CRM On Demand service. We will also use your name, and email address to communicate changes, events related to the Vtiger CRM On Demand service.
  * 3rd party Information: While using the Vtiger CRM On Demand service, you will be entering details of your clients, such as Contacts and Accounts, uploading documents..etc. None of this information is used by Vtiger CRM On Demand service for any purpose other than fulfilling the functions requested by you.
  * Usage Details: Your usage details such as time, frequency, duration, pattern of use, features used and amount of storage used might be recorded by us and used to improve the Vtiger CRM On Demand service.
  * Financial Information: In case of services requiring payment, we request credit card or other payment account information, which will be used solely for processing payments. 

### Storage Premises

  * The data stored in your user account, including documents, emails, contact details, invoices, ..etc, will be stored on the servers of our Cloud infrastructure provider. These servers are located in the United States and other countries. Use of Vtiger CRM On Demand service signifies your consent to such transfer of your data outside of your country.
  * In order to prevent loss of data due to errors or system failures, we also keep backup copies of data including the contents of your user account. Hence your files and data may remain on our servers even after deletion or termination of your user account. We assure you that the contents of your user account will not be disclosed to anyone. We also do not process the contents of your user account for serving targeted advertisements.

### Use of Cookies

We use temporary and permanent cookies to enhance your experience of our Vtiger CRM On Demand services. Temporary cookies will be removed from your computer each time you close your browser. By selecting ‘keep me signed-in’ option in Vtiger CRM On Demand Services, a permanent cookie will be stored in your computer and you will not be required to sign-in by providing complete login information each time you return to our website. If you have turned cookies off, you may not be able to use registered areas of the website. We tie cookie information to your email address when you elect to remain logged in so as to maintain and recall your preferences within the website.

### Use of Web beacons

Web beacons are 1x1 clear images that are embedded onto a web page or an email to document traffic and for website analytics without collecting any Personal Information. To provide the service, we may from time to time employ the use of web beacons on the website and in emails.

### 3rd Party Analytics Services

We may employ the services of a third party agent to analyze statistical and aggregate data about our website content and user base. This aggregated information is not personally identifiable and is employed in improving website functionality and offerings. To this end, these third parties may employ the use of cookies and, or pixel tags in providing their services. While these third party cookies are not tied to your Personal Information, Vtiger CRM On Demand does not have access to these cookies nor are we responsible for them.

### Links from our website

Some pages of our website contain external links. You are advised to verify the privacy practices of such other websites. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you at such other websites. We encourage you not to provide Personal Information, without assuring yourselves of the Privacy Policy Statement of other websites.

### With whom we share Information

We may need to disclose Personal Information to our affiliates, service providers and business partners solely for the purpose of providing Vtiger CRM On Demand services to you. For example, if you request that a sales person contact you, we may pass your request to a local reseller partner, if that is appropriate. In such cases Vtiger will also ensure that such affiliates, service providers and business partners comply with this Privacy Policy Statement and adopt appropriate confidentiality and security measures. We will obtain your prior specific consent before we share or disclose your Personal Information to any person outside Vtiger for any purpose that is not directly connected with providing Vtiger CRM On Demand Services to you. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any Personal Information regarding visitors and users with our business partners. Please be aware that laws in various jurisdictions in which we operate may obligate us to disclose user information and the contents of your user account to the local law enforcement authorities under a legal process or an enforceable government request.  In addition, we may also disclose Personal Information and contents of your user account to law enforcement authorities if such disclosure is determined to be necessary by Vtiger in our sole and absolute discretion for protecting the safety of our users, employees, or the general public.

### How secure is your Information

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of the personal information and data stored in your account. Access to your name and email address is restricted to the employees of Vtiger. Data stored in your account is only accessed by the Vtiger team when performing migration, or support services.

All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

### Your Choice in Information Use

You will be required to register for our Vtiger CRM On Demand service by providing Personal Information. If you choose not to provide your Personal Information, we will be unable to provide you the Vtiger CRM On Demand service.  We will provide you with the option of opting out from receiving mail from us; however, you will not be able to receive email notifications of new services, releases, upcoming events and changes to the Privacy Policy Statement should you decide to opt-out of receiving all messages from Vtiger. In the event we decide to use your Personal Information for any purpose other than as stated in this Privacy Policy Statement, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of your Personal Information for those other purposes. You may opt out of receiving newsletters and other secondary messages from Vtiger by selecting the ‘unsubscribe’ function present in every message we send.

### Accessing, Updating and Removing Personal Information

We provide users with access to their Personal Information. Users may correct, update or remove any such Personal Information either by accessing their user account or by contacting Vtiger Support . Such changes may take up to 48 hours to take effect. We respond to all enquiries within 30 days.

### Investigation of Illegal Activity

We may need to provide access to your Personal Information and the contents of your user account to our employees and service providers for the purpose of investigating any suspected illegal activity or potential violation of the terms and conditions for use of Vtiger CRM On Demand Services. However, Vtiger will ensure that such access is in compliance with this Privacy Policy Statement and subject to appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

### Children's Privacy

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

### Enforcement of Privacy Policy

We make every effort, including periodic reviews to ensure that Personal Information provided by you is used in conformity with this Privacy Policy Statement. If you have any concerns regarding our adherence to this Privacy Policy Statement or the manner in which Personal Information is used for the purpose of providing Vtiger CRM On Demand Services, kindly contact our Support team at [od-support@vtiger.com](mailto:od-support@vtiger.com) This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it . We will contact you to address your concerns and we will also co-operate with regulatory authorities in this regard if needed.

### Notification of Changes

Any changes to the Privacy Policy Statement will be posted on our website in order to keep you informed of any changes in nature of information collected, manner of collection, use and sharing of information. If at any point we decide to use Personal Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses unless you have opted out from receiving all email notifications from us. You will not receive email notification of minor changes to the Privacy Policy Statement. If you are concerned about how your personal information is used, you should check this page periodically.

### Blogs and Forums

We provide the capacity for users to post information in blogs and forums for sharing information in a public space on the website. This information is publicly available to all users of these forums and visitors to Vtiger sites. We require registration to publish information, but given the public nature of both platforms, any Personal Information disclosed within these forums may be used to contact users with unsolicited messages. We encourage users to be cautious in disclosure of Personal Information in public forums as Vtiger is not responsible for the Personal Information users elect to disclose.

Vtiger also supports third party widgets on the website that allow users to share articles and other information on different platforms. These widgets do not collect or store any Personal Information from users on the website and simply act as a bridge for your convenience in sharing information.

### End of Privacy Policy

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy Statement, please contact us at [legal@vtiger.com](mailto:legal@vtiger.com). We will respond to all inquiries within 30 days of receipt after ascertaining your identity.
